<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<FundingAwardNotice xmlns="urn:xmlns:nl:pop-project:cerif-profile-1.0-EXPERIMENTAL"
                    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
                    xsi:schemaLocation="urn:xmlns:nl:pop-project:cerif-profile-1.0-EXPERIMENTAL ../schemas/p-o-p-profile-schema2.xsd urn:xmlns:nl:pop-project:vocab:Subjects# ../schemas/subjects.xsd">
   <!-- A fictitious project funding award notice based on a real-world project, see http://www.narcis.nl/research/RecordID/OND1315843 -->
   <Project id="d12575">
      <Title xml:lang="en">New frontiers in imaging the brain: A proposal for a national brain imaging resource</Title>
      <Identifier type="urn:xmlns:nl:pop-project:vocab:IdentifierTypes#narcis">OND1315843</Identifier>
      <Identifier type="urn:xmlns:nl:pop-project:vocab:IdentifierTypes#source-url">http://www.narcis.nl/research/RecordID/OND1315843</Identifier>
      <StartDate>2006-01-01</StartDate>
      <EndDate>2017-12-31</EndDate>
      <Funders>
         <Funder>
            <OrgUnit id="d5">
               <Acronym>NWO</Acronym>
               <Name xml:lang="en">Netherlands Organisation for Scientific Research</Name>
               <Name xml:lang="nl">Nederlandse Organisatie voor Wetenschappelijk Onderzoek</Name>
               <Identifier type="urn:xmlns:nl:pop-project:vocab:IdentifierTypes#FundRefId">http://dx.doi.org/10.13039/501100003246</Identifier>
               <Identifier type="urn:xmlns:nl:pop-project:vocab:IdentifierTypes#narcis">ORG1236737</Identifier>
               <Identifier type="urn:xmlns:nl:pop-project:vocab:IdentifierTypes#source-url">http://www.narcis.nl/organisation/RecordID/ORG1236737</Identifier>
            </OrgUnit>
         </Funder>
      </Funders>
      <Consortium>
         <Secretariat>
            <OrgUnit id="d266">
               <Name xml:lang="en">Department of Cognitive Psychology</Name>
               <Name xml:lang="nl">Leerstoelgroep Cognitieve Psychologie</Name>
               <Identifier type="urn:xmlns:nl:pop-project:vocab:IdentifierTypes#narcis">ORG1235703</Identifier>
               <Identifier type="urn:xmlns:nl:pop-project:vocab:IdentifierTypes#source-url">http://www.narcis.nl/organisation/RecordID/ORG1235703</Identifier>
               <PartOf>
                  <OrgUnit id="d51">
                     <Name xml:lang="en">Faculty of Social Sciences</Name>
                     <Name xml:lang="nl">Faculteit der Sociale Wetenschappen</Name>
                     <Identifier type="urn:xmlns:nl:pop-project:vocab:IdentifierTypes#narcis">ORG1238279</Identifier>
                     <Identifier type="urn:xmlns:nl:pop-project:vocab:IdentifierTypes#source-url">http://www.narcis.nl/organisation/RecordID/ORG1238279</Identifier>
                     <PartOf>
                        <OrgUnit id="d11">
                           <Acronym>RU</Acronym>
                           <Name xml:lang="en">Radboud University Nijmegen</Name>
                           <Name xml:lang="nl">Radboud Universiteit Nijmegen</Name>
                           <Identifier type="urn:xmlns:nl:pop-project:vocab:IdentifierTypes#narcis">ORG1236841</Identifier>
                           <Identifier type="urn:xmlns:nl:pop-project:vocab:IdentifierTypes#source-url">http://www.narcis.nl/organisation/RecordID/ORG1236841</Identifier>
                        </OrgUnit>
                     </PartOf>
                  </OrgUnit>
               </PartOf>
            </OrgUnit>
         </Secretariat>
      </Consortium>
      <Team>
         <PrincipalInvestigator>
            <DisplayName>Prof.dr. P. (Peter) Hagoort</DisplayName>
            <Person id="d3365">
               <PersonName>
                  <FamilyNames>Hagoort</FamilyNames>
                  <FirstNames>P. (Peter)</FirstNames>
               </PersonName>
               <Identifier type="urn:xmlns:nl:pop-project:vocab:IdentifierTypes#narcis">PRS1240840</Identifier>
               <Identifier type="urn:xmlns:nl:pop-project:vocab:IdentifierTypes#source-url">http://www.narcis.nl/person/RecordID/PRS1240840</Identifier>
               <Identifier type="urn:xmlns:nl:pop-project:vocab:IdentifierTypes#isni">0000 0001 1616 1122</Identifier>
               <Identifier type="urn:xmlns:nl:pop-project:vocab:IdentifierTypes#dai">info:eu-repo/dai/nl/069190372</Identifier>
            </Person>
            <Affiliation>
               <OrgUnit id="d3366">
                  <Name xml:lang="en">Donders Centre for Cognitive Neuroimaging</Name>
                  <Identifier type="urn:xmlns:nl:pop-project:vocab:IdentifierTypes#narcis">ORG1241082</Identifier>
                  <Identifier type="urn:xmlns:nl:pop-project:vocab:IdentifierTypes#source-url">http://www.narcis.nl/organisation/RecordID/ORG1241082</Identifier>
                  <PartOf>
                     <OrgUnit id="d260">
                        <Name xml:lang="en">Donders Institute for Brain, Cognition and Behaviour</Name>
                        <Identifier type="urn:xmlns:nl:pop-project:vocab:IdentifierTypes#narcis">ORG1243002</Identifier>
                        <Identifier type="urn:xmlns:nl:pop-project:vocab:IdentifierTypes#source-url">http://www.narcis.nl/organisation/RecordID/ORG1243002</Identifier>
                        <PartOf>
                           <OrgUnit id="d11"/>
                        </PartOf>
                     </OrgUnit>
                  </PartOf>
               </OrgUnit>
            </Affiliation>
            <Affiliation>
               <OrgUnit id="d3366"/>
            </Affiliation>
            <Affiliation>
               <OrgUnit id="d3360">
                  <Name xml:lang="en">Department of Psycholinguistics</Name>
                  <Name xml:lang="nl">Leerstoelgroep Psycholinguïstiek</Name>
                  <Identifier type="urn:xmlns:nl:pop-project:vocab:IdentifierTypes#narcis">ORG1243751</Identifier>
                  <Identifier type="urn:xmlns:nl:pop-project:vocab:IdentifierTypes#source-url">http://www.narcis.nl/organisation/RecordID/ORG1243751</Identifier>
                  <PartOf>
                     <OrgUnit id="d51"/>
                  </PartOf>
               </OrgUnit>
            </Affiliation>
            <Affiliation>
               <OrgUnit id="d3368">
                  <Name xml:lang="en">Max Planck Institute for Psycholinguistics</Name>
                  <Identifier type="urn:xmlns:nl:pop-project:vocab:IdentifierTypes#narcis">ORG1236169</Identifier>
                  <Identifier type="urn:xmlns:nl:pop-project:vocab:IdentifierTypes#source-url">http://www.narcis.nl/organisation/RecordID/ORG1236169</Identifier>
               </OrgUnit>
            </Affiliation>
            <Affiliation>
               <OrgUnit id="d260"/>
            </Affiliation>
         </PrincipalInvestigator>
      </Team>
      <Subject xmlns="urn:xmlns:nl:pop-project:vocab:Subjects#">D51000</Subject>
      <Abstract xml:lang="en">Brain Imaging is a field that has developed at a rapid pace, and has greatly advanced the areas of cognitive and clinical neuroscience. Cognitive neuroscience aims at understanding the functional and neural architecture of cognitive functions such as perception, action, attention, memory, language, learning and consciousness. It also includes the study of emotion, social function (social neuroscience), decision making (neuroeconomics) and executive function. An important societal aspect of cognitive neuroscience is that our dynamic society demands lifelong learning. This requires that our learning environment should be designed in such a way that it is tailored to the learning capacities of the human brain (neuroplasticity), to be maximally effective. Clinical neuroscience aims at understanding, diagnosing and treating diseases of the central nervous system, such as dementia, stroke, epilepsy and psychiatric disorders. In the aging society, brain related diseases are an increasing cost factor. In the EU, brain related diseases consume 35% of the total budget for medical care. A knowledge based society with a high potential for innovation is helped tremendously by a better understanding of the organ that is the prerequisite for knowledge and innovation: the human brain. Therefore, both from a scientific and from a societal point of view, brain imaging is one of the most challenging research areas of the 21st century. Recent breakthroughs in cognitive neuroscience as well as in the understanding, diagnosis and treatment of brain diseases, have strongly relied on the availability of neuroimaging techniques that have allowed us to investigate the human brain in action. These techniques include (f)MRI, PET, EEG, and MEG. While traditionally The Netherlands has been strong in the fields of cognitive and clinical neuroscience, until recently there was a shortage of advanced neuroimaging equipment available for scientific research. This situation has improved in recent years, with the advent of research-dedicated neuroimaging facilities at several universities. However, the pace of technological development is extremely fast in the field of neuroimaging. MR-scanners at higher field strengths and with parallel imaging capabilities, MEG systems with increasing numbers of sensors, and experimental imaging facilities for animal studies open up new vistas for cognitive neuroscience research. It would be regrettable if The Netherlands were to lose the internationally competitive position that it has acquired in recent years, by not acting proactively. Hence, we herewith submit a proposal that will create an imaging infrastructure that is unique in the world and will keep The Netherlands at the cutting edge of neuroimaging research for years to come. This infrastructure will be exploited in a single new national research platform, The Netherlands Brain Imaging Resource (NBIR). The integrated neuroimaging infrastructure that we propose requires facilities for MR imaging at the highest field strengths currently possible in humans (7 T), similar facilities for animal scanning to allow for translational research, and the most advanced MEG imaging system. We will thus be able to combine the highest spatial resolution (MR) with the best temporal resolution (MEG). The rationale for the different modalities will now be described in more detail. An important component for which we ask financial support is MR imaging at 7 T. Magnetic Resonance Imaging (MRI) is a technique that has developed at a fast pace over the past twenty years: presently it plays a central role in both medicine and cognitive neuroscience. An important new development in MRI research is the availability of human MRI systems operating at ultra high magnetic field strengths. In several research institutes abroad, such systems are now becoming available, whereas in The Netherlands they are absent. This is deleterious for Dutch MRI research as scientists will no longer be able to perform cutting edge research. Another component of the NIBR for which funding is requested is a sy stem for Magneto-Encephalography (MEG). Major progress in neuroimaging is expected from combining different imaging techniques (multimodal imaging). In this context, combining ultra high field MR with its superior spatial resolution with methods that capitalize on a high temporal resolution is of the utmost importance. The most advanced imaging technology with a superb temporal resolution is MEG. We therefore propose to supplement the advanced MR-imaging systems for scanning man and animals, with the most advanced MEG-system currently available. This requires an upgrade of the current MEG system at the F.C. Donders Centre. A final component of NBIR is animal MR. In fundamental biomedical research of intact animals, Magnetic Resonance is of growing importance as a non-invasive tool to assess morphology, physiology and metabolism. MR images of the brain using various animal models (e.g. mice, rats, monkey) have played an essential role in the knowledge we have today of the physiology and metabolism of the working brain. This includes changes in hemodynamics and neuro-signalling involved in cognitive processes. Basic knowledge gained in MR research on animal brains will guide our experimentation and clinical neuroimaging research in humans. The common effort of the three institutions involved, with the support of all University Medical Centres in The Netherlands, creates an unprecedented nationwide structure for large scale neuroimaging facilities. It has the following advantages. First, synergetic interactions between the three institutions will ensure a high international standing, and a research programme of greater impact than any single institution could hope to achieve. Second, an open access structure will be created which will allow access for researchers from Dutch research centres outside the host institutions. Third, a firm commitment by the three centres to act in unison in order to attract national and international funding will ensure a strong Dutch presence on the international stage. Fourth, this infrastructure will create unique possibilities for innovation, such as design and evaluation of probes and contrast agents for targeted imaging, testing of psycho- and neuropharmaca.</Abstract>
   </Project>
</FundingAwardNotice>
